<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sharp-tailed.github.io</title>
    <description>itsnothing.net blog</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 01:24:56 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 01:24:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>On MSPs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First, let’s note a couple things about them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;paid to secure &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; infrastructure - can’t even secure &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; infrastructure a majority of the time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;account for majority of large-scale attacks on FVEY by foreign gov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So can they really be trusted with our nation’s infrastructure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cold-hard-facts-produce-cold-hard-cash&quot;&gt;Cold hard facts produce cold hard cash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsa.gov/Press-Room/Press-Releases-Statements/Press-Release-View/Article/2677750/nsa-partners-release-cybersecurity-advisory-on-brute-force-global-cyber-campaign/&quot;&gt;GRU is performing brute force attacks since mid-2019&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;incredibly easy to brute force &lt;em&gt;en mass&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Russian General Staff Main Intelligence Directorate(GRU) 85&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;
Main Special Service Center (GTsSS)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://media.defense.gov/2021/Jul/01/2002753896/-1/-1/1/CSA_GRU_GLOBAL_BRUTE_FORCE_CAMPAIGN_UOO158036-21.PDF&quot;&gt;GRU Conducting Global Brute Force Campaign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/news/microsoft-update-brute-force-password-spraying&quot;&gt;Microsoft advisory - NOBELIUM&lt;/a&gt;
(pt 1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2021/06/25/new-nobelium-activity/&quot;&gt;Microsoft blog - NOBELIUM APT&lt;/a&gt; (pt 2)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/guidance/phishing&quot;&gt;Phishing is such a massive revenue generator, it’s used against MSPs&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/files/phishing_case_study.pdf&quot;&gt;Case study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;msps-dont-use-basic-domain-protections&quot;&gt;MSPs don’t use basic domain protections:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;multi-layer security/restriction approach involving people and processes
   (&lt;a href=&quot;2022.0727.2129&quot;&gt;OSI Model&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SSO (application and network layer)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a requirements engineering process [Zowghi2000ARE] [Faroom2019]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SPF and DMARC (e-mail threats)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;network segregation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;least privilege&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;depreciate obsolete accounts and processes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;maintenance and updates regularly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rolling backups on-prem and in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mandatory Access Controls&lt;/em&gt; (SELinux, SSO, network permissions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These truly are basic fundamentals of security and should be utilized at the
bare minimum by companies paid to protect the infrastructure and systems (e.g.,
applications and controllers) of SMB’s and large companies. But they’re just
not. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/08/02/on-MSPs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/08/02/on-MSPs.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OSI Model</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please Do Not Throw Sausage Pizza Away&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical - data, cables, cat6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data - Switching. MAC addresses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network - IP addresses, routing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transport - TCP/UDP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Session - session management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentation - WMV, JPEG, MOV (media)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application - HTTP, SMTP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/07/27/OSI-model.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/07/27/OSI-model.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Windows 11</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows 11 is trying to take away your autonomy by imposing lockdown and -
while this may not be new - it has evolved slowly into a monopoly over your
data. Now you are locked into their services; &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; cloud, &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt;
software, &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; hardware modules. They have been boiling you slowly in a
pot for so long, you are becoming comfortable with it, and even, in some
extreme cases, you are &lt;strong&gt;forced&lt;/strong&gt; to get into the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want encryption and you’re not tech savvy, you’re forced to use Windows’ 
encryption software (Bitlocker). If you want to save your data but aren’t
tech savvy, you likely turn to easy solutions like this because it’s what is
shipped in Windows Home. The average consumer is very forcibly “asked” to use
their software and hardware in order to keep you so walled in that you can’t
function without them. It’s very hard, as with Google and its parent company
Alphabet, to switch out of this mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a prison but you can break free.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/07/01/Windows-11.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/07/01/Windows-11.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I tried many things, but..</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I find that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zettlr.com/&quot;&gt;Zettlr&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;em&gt;ˈset·lər&lt;/em&gt;] and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/&quot;&gt;Zotero&lt;/a&gt; make my life easier. I
have used it to make bibliographies with several papers now, all while
keeping a digital &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikiless.org/wiki/Zettelkasten&quot;&gt;Zettelkasten&lt;/a&gt;. It just requires knowledge of Markdown
syntax and how to use Zettlr for note-taking. The best part is how easy it
is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just need to download the extension for Zotero which is what you will be
using to create citations – without having to install plugins on the website.
You simply open Zotero, create a “Collection”, then you add references as you
browse. If you go to a link in your browser and click the “Save to Zotero”
button for the extension (it’s available for both Firefox and Chrome/Chromium
browsers), you can save multiple references in your Collection. This allows
you to, when done, simply export to a bibliography in various formats. It
makes note-taking a breeze and it improves your ability to read without
having to stop so often to manually write up your references and lookup
things. There is a very handy setting in Zotero that allows to import all
metadata for a certain DOI or arxiv number, just by pasting the number into
the “Add Item(s) by Identifier” button. It pulls all the information for you
in a second. No more manual references. The only thing is you will have to
manually set the reference pointers like I have done in this post. Numbering
and setting the #refs themselves is pretty easy, just create a numbered list
in the markdown editor or your IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/13/zettling-in.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/06/13/zettling-in.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What exactly does Windows collect on you? Well..</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just from one angle, the Bluetooth and Wi-Fi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geo-location via Wi-Fi &amp;amp; Bluetooth: Whether it is Android, iOS, Windows,
macOS, or even Ubuntu. Most popular Operating Systems now collect telemetry
information by default even if you never opt-in or opted-out from the start.
Some like Windows will not even allow disabling telemetry completely without
some technical tweaks. This information collection can be extensive and
include a staggering number of details (metadata and data) on your devices
and their usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Itemized lists&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/privacy/required-windows-diagnostic-data-events-and-fields-2004&quot;&gt;Full list of required diagnostic data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/privacy/windows-diagnostic-data&quot;&gt;Full list of optional diagnostic data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;W10Privacy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w10privacy.de/english-home/&quot;&gt;W10Privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right-click&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Run as administrator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check all the recommended (Green) settings and save.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional but recommended (but could break things, use at your own risk), also
check the orange/red settings, and save.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reboot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WindowsSpyBlocker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download and run &lt;a href=&quot;https://crazymax.dev/WindowsSpyBlocker/download/&quot;&gt;WindowsSpyBlocker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; and go into &lt;strong&gt;Telemetry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; and go into &lt;strong&gt;Firewall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; and add &lt;strong&gt;Spy Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reboot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Also, consider using O&amp;amp;O ShutUp10++:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download and run &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oo-software.com/en/shutup10&quot;&gt;O&amp;amp;O ShutUp10++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enable &lt;em&gt;at least&lt;/em&gt; all of the recommended settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Privacy&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Diagnostic&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Delete all Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will need to update and re-run W10Privacy and WindowsSpyBlocker frequently
 and after any Windows update as they tend to silently re-enable telemetry using
 those updates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus, it could be interesting to also consider
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/beerisgood/windows10_hardening&quot;&gt;hardening your Windows host&lt;/a&gt;.
(This is a security guide, not a privacy guide.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://anonymousplanet-ng.org/&quot;&gt;The Hitchhiker’s Guide to Online Anonymity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I am a maintainer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/what-windows-does-with-all-your-data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/what-windows-does-with-all-your-data.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Take back control of your data</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;Steps:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embrace a zero trust model.
Don’t rely on reactive security practices.
Never trust. Always verify.
Never put all your eggs into one basket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are ~3 things you should absolutely be doing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Better passwords:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;go change them all, &lt;strong&gt;seriously, right now!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use strong/non-unique passwords (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/grempe/diceware&quot;&gt;diceware&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;never mix or reuse them across services/accounts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use a password manager (preferably offline, like KeePassXC)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;avoid sharing passwords and use something that notifies you of breaches
(but don’t rely solely on reactive security)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;enable 2FA/MFA, possibly use hardware keys/tokens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;backup everything just in case&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;update your OS with security updates and employ active IDS/IPS (it’s not as
hard as it sounds)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;disable and/or avoid telemetry from your OS, browser and IoT devices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t use browser storage for sensitive info including passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Better browsing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;block ads at the host level (Pi-hole, DNSSEC/DNSCRYPT, /etc/hosts, router VPN)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;uBlock Origin, LibRedirect, Smart Referrer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ensure website integrity (in Tor, you can verify a site’s /mirrors.txt)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use a private search engine (SearXNG, DuckDuckGo, Brave)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t use unnecessary extensions (cf.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arkenfox/user.js/wiki/4.1-Extensions#-dont-bother&quot;&gt;https://github.com/arkenfox/user.js/wiki/4.1-Extensions&lt;/a&gt;) -
useless bullshit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use HTTPS (default in your regular browser usually)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DNS over HTTPS (DOH)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;containerize and/or sanitize browsing in-between sessions, 
(again, Arkenfox/user.js)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minimize your footprint/fingerprint (Firefox FRP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;plain-text emails only, question all attachments from all sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Practice your OPSEC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t login on another person’s device and use privacy shields if you can&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;avoid password hints or use answers that have nothing to do with them
(confuse the enemy :))&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;don’t use a 4-digit pin for your devices, use a strong password&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minimize or eliminate the SMS 2FA for services to avoid SIM swaps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;avoid using your password manager for OTP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;avoid face and biometric unlocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;never reuse usernames&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;use a mail forwarding service to combat spam (and further confuse the enemy)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Lissy93/personal-security-checklist&quot;&gt;personal security checklist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/take-back-control.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/06/12/take-back-control.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Removing microdots from printed documents</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anonymize your documents by removing metadata and ensure you don’t have any
identifying marks embedded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For hundreds of years, paper and printing techniques are the foundation for
distribution of information. Thereby, physical documents enjoy high
confidence. To have something in “black and white” carries significance. But
forgery or alteration of documents are nearly as old as the history of
writing. Hence the question for the originator is important. Nowadays,
because of continual technological development, even individuals can print
high-quality documents and duplicates. This can be done with cheap and
customary devices. In addition image processing software, like GIMP or Adobe
Photoshop, allows to manipulate documents and images easily. Therefore
printed documents are often an issue in crimes, e.g. faked proof of identity,
copyright theft, or as exhibit in a criminal case. In all this cases it could
be useful for law enforcement agencies to, e.g., identify the device or model
which was used to print the questionable document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary focus of the research lies on the extraction of artifacts, which
are originated from the print process. These artifacts emerge particularly
through electromechanical imperfections and also through differences between
constructions of printer models. We try to find and analyze artifacts which
are stable and e.g. model specific and therefore usable as intrinsic
signatures for a specific printer model. The extraction of these signatures
should be conducted with customary scanner devices and image processing
techniques. Simultaneously, the company Dence (cooperation partner) will
investigate the scanner forensics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of the project deals with research of print-scan resilient
checks of duplicates. Here the knowledge about artifacts which occur in the
print and scan process represent a reliable basis. As use case the typical
workflow in an insurance can be mentioned. In the event of damage, the
insured person would take a photo of the damage and send it postal, together
with forms, to the insurance. Afterwards the insurance will scan these
documents. The insurance staff examines the event of damage on the basis of
the digital reproduction. Because of the print and scan processes, which the
original document went through, the question of authenticity of the document
is difficulty to answer. Goal of the analysis is the implementation of an
image search for duplicates, which is resilient against the print and scan
process. This means, that images can also be matched, if only printed and
re-digitized versions are available. The duplicate testing must be able to
check an image immediately against a data pool with millions of images. From
technical view, this will be realized with a distinct image hash. The
challenge for the print-scan scenario is the computation of this hash. The
hash value has to be equal or very similar between the original photo and the
printed and re-digitized image, so that they can matched. Another difficulty
is a working check for duplicates also with slight manipulations in the
image (like a car scratch). All of this must be accomplished without matching
false positives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://dfd.inf.tu-dresden.de/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://github.com/dfd-tud/deda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/09/microdots-and-nuking-them.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/06/09/microdots-and-nuking-them.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Telegram is Giving Data to German Feds in Certain Cases</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Telegram has provided the German Federal Criminal Police Office with user
information in several cases, contradicting the company’s statements about
complying with law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telegram, which is not an encrypted messaging application by default, released
user data to the Federal Criminal Police Office (BKA) in several cases,
according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20220605102156/https://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/apps/telegram-gibt-nutzerdaten-an-das-bundeskriminalamt-a-0e4d3fcb-8081-4b87-b062-db412bbc294b&quot; title=&quot;Telegram hält sich neuerdings an Gesetze, zumindest ein bisschen&quot;&gt;a report from Spiegel&lt;/a&gt;. According
to the news outlet, Telegram handed over subscriber information for the suspects
in “child abuse and terrorism” investigations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20220605091308/https://telegram.org/faq#q-what-are-your-thoughts-on-internet-privacy&quot; title=&quot;Telegram FAQ&quot;&gt;The company claims&lt;/a&gt; that they have disclosed “0 bytes of user data” to law
enforcement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do you process data requests?
“Secret chats use end-to-end encryption, thanks to which we don’t have any
data to disclose.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To protect the data that is not covered by end-to-end encryption, Telegram
uses a distributed infrastructure. Cloud chat data is stored in multiple data
centers around the globe that are controlled by different legal entities spread
across different jurisdictions. The relevant decryption keys are split into
parts and are never kept in the same place as the data they protect. As a
result, several court orders from different jurisdictions are required to force
us to give up any data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Thanks to this structure, we can ensure that no single government or block of
like-minded countries can intrude on people’s privacy and freedom of expression.
Telegram can be forced to give up data only if an issue is grave and universal
enough to pass the scrutiny of several different legal systems around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;To this day, we have disclosed 0 bytes of user data to third parties,
including governments.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://darknetlive.com/post/telegram-handing-data-over-to-german-feds/images/rq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Spiegel, “it is still difficult for German investigators to
obtain information from Telegram” when investigating crimes outside of the
scope of purported “terrorism” or child abuse. Since 2018, if not earlier,
the company has been moving towards a state of functional compliance with
various Western governments. A privacy policy change in 2018 allowed for the
disclosure of IP addresses and phone numbers if required by a court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paragraph below appears under a section titled, “Who Your Personal Data
May Be Shared With” in &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20220605092126/https://telegram.org/privacy#2-legal-ground-for-processing-your-personal-data&quot; title=&quot;Telegram Privacy Policy&quot;&gt;the company’s privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Law Enforcement Authorities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If Telegram receives a court order that confirms you’re a terror suspect, we
may disclose your IP address and phone number to the relevant authorities. So
far, this has never happened. When it does, we will include it in a semiannual
transparency report published at:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/transparency.%22&quot;&gt;https://t.me/transparency.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments have historically used the “terrorism loophole” to justify invasive
measures. Since the United States spies on Americans for counterterrorism
purposes, there is no reason to believe Germany would not use the same excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/08/telegram-giving-data-to-feds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022/06/08/telegram-giving-data-to-feds.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
